David Simon Tetruashvili

UNDERGRADUATE COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT - TINKEREE

Lambeth, London, United Kingdom. · Berlin, Germany.

□ (+44) (0) 786-407-5561 · (+49) (0) 172-323-0427 | ■ david.tetruashvili@kcl.ac.uk | 🖸 davzzar | 🛅 DavidSTetruashvli

"The best oportunity comes when you find you need somethig that does not exists yet."

Profile

I am a striving trilingual Computer Science bachelor student with an international background to specialise in Artificial Intelligence at King's College London who puts much focus on crafting elegant solutions from the get-go and then improving on them. I follow the CTF hacking competition scene; you can often find me reading write-ups from past conventions though I am yet to attend one. I enjoy to customise and frequently change my Linux desktop environment and tinker with my terminal emulator. Currently I am working on my final diploma project: an Argumentation Framework Solver under the supervision of Dr Odinaldo Rogrigues.

Skills

Languages English, German, Russian

Programming Python, C/C++, Java, Scala, NodeJS/JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, NoSQL (Firebase)

Tools (Arch) Linux, Zsh/Bash, Git & GitHub, Digital Ocean

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (WITH ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE) (HONS.)

Misc. Video Editing (Adobe Premier Pro), Arduino & basic electronics

Education

King's College London — University of London

London, United Kingdom

Sep. 2017 - Present

• Current GPA: 89%

- Expected first-class degree.
- · Relevant modules include:

Software Engineering Group Project [Major Project ("Prep."): 91%, Written Examination: 92% (Top mark in class), Overall: 87%],

Introduction to Artificial Intelligence [Coursework #1: 85%, Coursework #2: 90%, Overall: 84%],

Practical Experiences of Programming (C++/Scala) [91%], Programming Practice and Applications (Java) [96%],

Internet Systems [97% (Top mark in class)], Database Systems (MySQL) [90%],

with seven other modules with final grades between 82% and 90%.

Berlin International School Berlin, German

INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE DIPLOMA

Sep. 2015 - May 2017

- Overall 42 points out of possible 45, including 6/7 points in Higher Level Mathematics.
- Extended Essay in Computer Science on *Evaluation of Texture Filtering Algorithms applied in VR HUDs*: **33/36 points, Grade A**.

International-GCSE Sep. 2015 - May 2017

• 10 IGCSEs with eight being A* or A, including A*s in Mathematics, Physics, and ICT.

Experience_

Guy's and St. Thomas' Hospital NHS Trust

London, United Kingdom

MOBILE APP DEVELOPED & DATABASE ENGINEER

Feb. - Mar. 2019

- Developed a Doctor-Patient communication and test compliance mobile application (iOS and Android) and admin web app (Vue.js) package called "Prep." in a team of 8 as the "Major Project" during the 2nd year at KCL.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Managed and maintained a consistent Git version control history and conventions for the whole duration of the project.}$
- Designed and implemented several mobile application modules intended for use by patients aged c. between 40 and 60 years old focusing on accessibility, utilising Google's Flutter framework.
- Prototyped/Designed the UI theme and other UI elements for the mobile application with emphasis on ease of use and readability.
- Designed and implemented the back-end database structure used for the app with hard emphasis on privacy, information leak prevention, and enterprise scalability using Google's NoSQL Firebase database.
- Created a screencast presenting the final application.
- · Solution has been shortlisted for funding.



Collegiate Information Portal (KCL-info)

Designer and Programmer Oct. 2019 – Present

Currently developing an information retrieval web API for use by staff and students of KCL. The main purpose is to provide easy access to important and up-to-date information around campus and all of its aspects in one unified place.

KCLge Game Rental Catalogue Web App

Back-end Developer Nov. – Dec. 2018

In a team of two, developed back-end for a online-store-style web app using pure PHP and JavaScript to access an external API for game data to be cached in a MySQL database. Implemented CRUD administrative functionality including multiple account types (guest/user/admin system), game information manipulation and editing and entry, and basic rental functionality such as renting rule/restriction definition and enforcement, black-listing, and game inventory management.

Extracurricular Activity & Volunteering

TeachFirst (Placed at Harris Academy Packham)

Peckham, London, United Kingdom

INSIGHT PROGRAMME INTERN

- Jun. 2018
- Underwent crash-course-style pedagogic training focusing on self-development in problem solving, leadership, and innovation through workshops, lectures, and practical exercises.
- · Spent one week at Harris Academy Peckham serving as teaching assistant in the department of mathematics.
- Planned, prepared resources for, and delivered a mathematics lesson to a year 8 set 1 class.
- Observing teacher noted "outstanding use of pre-prepared resources, great rapport built with students, and positive and motivational attitude."

Modern Language Center at King's College London

London, United Kingdom

GERMAN AND RUSSIAN LANGUAGE TUTOR

Apr. 2019 – Present

· Volunteered time to run speaking practice sessions with students at the university and persons of the public.

Beginner's Programming and Game Development Workshop

Berlin, Germany

WORKSHOP LEADER

- May. Jul. 2017
- Launched an after school beginner's programming workshop after learning that the school did not offer adequate education in this topic 'due to low demand.'
- Thought the basics of programming to a class of c. 30 students of mixed ages using Python 3 and the simple 2D game engine GameMakerStudio.
- This effort was acknowledged in the school's yearbook that year.